{
    "id": "f72279ad294a496abd63a369139b8e25",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It was my manager …………………… sent the parcel to James yesterday.",
            "description": "In structures like these we can use the relative pronoun who or that to refer to a personal subject.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "It was the parcel …………………………. my brother sent to James yesterday.",
            "description": "Who cannot be used to refer to an object.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "who",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It is he …………………………. responsible.",
            "description": "In a formal style we use subject pronoun + who + verb in this structure.",
            "answers": [
                "who is",
                "that is"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It is me ………………………… responsible.",
            "description": "In an informal style we use ‘that + primary auxiliary’.",
            "answers": [
                "who am",
                "that is",
                "that am"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is you ………………………. in the wrong.",
            "description": "In an informal style ‘that is’ is also possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "who are",
                "that is",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. you need is rest.",
            "description": "All that can mean what.",
            "answers": [
                "All",
                "All that",
                "What",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. I did was to touch the vase, and it broke.",
            "description": "All that can mean what.",
            "answers": [
                "All",
                "All that",
                "What",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… where we live.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "That is",
                "There is",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The reason ………………………… I went to London was to see my cousin.",
            "description": "Reason can be followed by why or that.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "why",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We moved to the countryside so that the children would have a garden …………………….",
            "description": "In a less formal style we can use the infinitive + preposition instead of a relative pronoun. ",
            "answers": [
                "in which to play",
                "to play in",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She was miserable unless she had people ……………………………….",
            "description": "In a less formal style we can use the infinitive + preposition instead of a relative pronoun. ",
            "answers": [
                "with whom to talk",
                "to talk to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is that girl …………………………. next to Peter?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "sitting",
                "who is sitting",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}